dosa is my all time favourite breakfast recipe I can actually have
it any time during the day today we going to do a
very special masala for the dosa batter I am going to show
the rise in the Dal separately half cup of Idli rice add
half cup of purple rice what's the price of you Times porn
of water and soft rice for about 3 hours to another poll
take water cup of urad dal today's add half teaspoon of Fenugreek
seed half teaspoon chana dal what's the Dalo couple of times turn
off water and socket for about 3 hours let's add quarter cup
of Poha that is able you can use either variety washing foreign of water and sofa 3 hours
all the ingredients for the better has been soaking for about 3 hours
I am going to growing to talk together first add the rice remove
all the excess water first grind without adding any water very little water
at the soap dal
finally are the soap poha National water grind the batter till it comes to a nice smooth
consistency transfer the pattern to a bowl add half teaspoon of salt you can either at rock
salt or table Sal make sure you mix the butter well leave the better at room temperature
for about 8 hours for it to permit so the battle was ready to make dosa first
I'm going to make the spicy red chutney for the masala dosa for the sticker Pan at
2 teaspoons of oil add two tablespoons of chana dal next at one teaspoon of cumin seeds
next add one small size onion finely chopped at 6 large
closed garlic next at the Red Chillies last because they can
get burnt very quickly turn off the store cool the mixture
to this add half teaspoon of rock salt
four little water spicy recipes done keep the suicide for the potato
masala take a Kadai at one tablespoon of oil I am going
to temple a few ingredients starting with water teaspoon of mustard seeds
water teaspoon urad dal quarter teaspoon cumin seeds once the mustard seed
starts flattering at what is teaspoon of a spreading if you curry leaves
next add one large onion finally chart at two green chillies finally chopped what's the onions
are transparent and half teaspoon of turmeric powder one teaspoon salt I've taken three large potatoes
boiled peel the skin and current the pieces I am going to match the potato gently
finally at South Korean the leads turn off the store now will start making the
masala dosa just heated up but not way too hot while pouring the better keep
the flame on medium and make your those us spread the battery and circular motion
an oil or ghee for the dosa and adding ghee so we can do a nice
masala roast so you can see this nice colour it's forming in the nice reddish brown
colour set this point you can check yourself and slowly start turning into the other side
I am going to add the chutney spicy chutney just spread across take a teaspoon do not
too much it might become too spicy just a little keep a tablespoon masala like a little
more you can personality here de do you have a perfect cris delicious ghee masala so there
you go here is absolutely delicious masala dosa it is nice spicy chutney so you can see
we showed you all the techniques here so definitely do try and enjoy this spicy masala dosa
you can get a copy of a first edition of the home cooking book on 21 April